Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) Collection 104
People's Archive, MLK Library
Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) Collection
1912-1989
People's Archive, MLK Library
Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA)
104
0.5 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Clippings This series contains clippings from local newspapers regarding the YWCA. Series 2: Pamphlets and publications This series includes pamphlets and publications on membership, educational, recreational and health programs, and organizational information related to the YWCA.
Biographical / Historical
The YWCA of Washington, D.C. was organized on May 5, 1905 and incorporated later that year, on June 30. Bettie G. Francis served as the first President. By the end of its first year, the organization had 193 members. The original mission of the YWCA was "to provide employment, housing, and moral development for young women." Over the years, however, the organization's reach expanded to include programs for men, women, and children in all areas of health, fitness, education, career training, youth programs and the arts.
Custodial History
The provenance of this collection is unknown.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of clippings, pamphlets, promotional materials, and organizational information pertaining to the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) in Washington, D.C.
Associations, institutions, etc; Urban renewal; Gentrification; Education; Women; Physical fitness
- Series 1: Clippings
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains clippings from local newspapers regarding the YWCA.
  - Clippings, 1912-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1950-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Pamphlets and Publications
  This series includes pamphlets and publications on membership, educational, recreational and health programs, and organizational information.
  - Education, 1922-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Education, 1932-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1945-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Health and Recreation, 1921-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership, 1936-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Organizational Information, 1912-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)